Guide to the Jacob Henry Burn, Collection Towards Forming a History
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
"Collection towards forming a history of the now obsolete office of the Master of the Revells"
1874-1874
OSBORN D1
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.17
(1 volume)
Autograph MSS.
Burn, Jacob Henry, -1869
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a partial inventory of the contents of Osborn d1. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
English drama -- History; Royal households -- Great Britain; Theater -- Great Britain -- History; Women authors; England -- Genealogy; Great Britain -- Officials and employees; Buck, George, Sir, 1560?-1622; Burn, Jacob Henry, -1869; Herbert, Henry, Sir, 1595-1673; Killigrew, Charles, 1655-1724 or 1725; Killigrew, Thomas, 1612-1683
- Osborn d1: Partial List
  - BELTZ, GEORGE FREDERICK, 1777-1841
    - ALS to unnamed recipient, 1796 Sep 2 (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      College of Arms [London]
      3 p.; 21 x 18 cm.
      Lower part of the letter, with
      recipient's name cut off; concerns
      the office of the Master of the
      Revels.
      d1/33-34
  - CHADWICK, CHARLES
    - ALS to William Radclyffe (?1783-1855), 1813 Noc 23 (Box 1)
      Mavesyn-Ridware
      3 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
      d 1/42
  - HERBERT, SIR HENRY, 1595-1673
    - Memorandum: autograph MS, [1630 or later] (Box 1)
      1 p.; 12 x 10 cm.
      Lists holders of the office of the
      Master of the Revels from 1569-1630
      in the same volume (Osborn Shelves
      d 1/185) is a fragment of an
      autograph license issued by Herbert,
      dated 1636 Jul 12, as well as a
      document concerning disbursements of
      the Revels Office signed by Herbert's
      assistants (Osborn Shelves
      d 1/176-180).
      d 1/156; d 1/185; d 1/176-180
  - HERBERT, SIR HENRY, 1595-1673
    - Letter (draft) to Henry Hyde, 2nd earl of Clarendon (1638-1709) and Edward Montagu, 2nd earl of Manchester (1602-1671), 1662 Jul 11 (Box 1)
      Cary-house
      2 p.; 29 x 19 cm.
      Lists fees and profits of the office
      of the Master of the Revels and
      mentions his differences with Sir
      William D'Avenant (1606-1668).
      d 1/227-230
  - HAYWARD, AGNES
    - ALS to Anne Gawdye, 1586 Nov 24 (Box 1)
      London
      1 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      d 1/83
  - MADDOCKES, CHARLES
    - ALS to Edward Hopkins, 1722 Oct 3 (Box 1)
      Dublin Castle
      2 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      Congratulates Hopkins on his
      appointment as Master of the Revels
      in Ireland; in the same volume are
      copies of 3 letters from Maddockes to
      Hopkins, dated 1722 Oct 4,
      1722 Oct 10, and 1722 Oct 13.
      d 1/302 and d 1/304
  - KILLIGREW, CHARLES, 1655-1725
    - Signature, n.d. (Box 1)
      17 x 21 cm.
      On a fragment of a title-page removed
      from a printed book.
      d 1/288
  - REES, RICHARD
    - ALS to R. Triphook, 1819 Dec 24 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
      Letter solicits order for "The
      History of Richard the Third" by Sir
      George Buc [or Buck] (d. 1623) which
      is to be published by Rees; "now
      first printed entire from the
      original ms. in the possession of
      the editor...Charles Yarnold, Esq."
      is written on a blank leaf of printed
      proposals for this work.
      d 1/143